<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blogs on Egmont Mika</title>
    <link>http://egmontmika.com/blog/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blogs on Egmont Mika</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 07 Jun 2017 03:01:45 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://egmontmika.com/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Building a Fortune</title>
      <link>http://egmontmika.com/blog/building-a-fortune/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jun 2017 03:01:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://egmontmika.com/blog/building-a-fortune/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;You can’t buy trust.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yet, it’s one of the greatest assets you can have. It’s a fortune.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At first glance, building trust seems simple. You say what you are going to do and then do what you said. You keep your promises. You act out your words. Never giving less, rather a little more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Without any hidden agenda, without cutting corners. Without faking the results. And without covering up your mistakes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Without pretending.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Showing up on time - doing your work - completing it. Period.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No need to make it look fancier. No need to add more or better promises. Just keep the ones you already made. No need to improve your image; it’s not a matter of marketing, anyway.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just be the person you say you are and do what is right.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s as simple as that, indeed. But alas! It’s not always easy. We hardly get it without effort and sometimes it takes great courage. And for some of us it just seems impossible, as long as we are hiding something.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In order to build a fortune of trust, you’ve got to be honest. Absolutely, radically honest. At times, and for a while, this may make you look like a looser.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is a price to pay.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the long run, though, reliabilty and honesty will pay and amount to much.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Hello friends!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This was my last blogpost for this season. The school year in Sweden is rapidly coming to an end and it&amp;rsquo;s time for a summer break.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thank you for reading my articles and joining me in the journey. I hope you enjoyed reading at least some of them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ll be back to you in September. Would you like to get a reminder by email? Then, make sure you have signed up by entering your email address in the top right corner of this page.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And, in case you never commented on any of my blogposts since last fall, this is the last chance you can do it. I&amp;rsquo;d love to hear from you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Have a nice summer.
Be blessed with the joy in the Lord!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yours,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Egmont&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Don&#39;t Go to Church!</title>
      <link>http://egmontmika.com/blog/don%27t-go-to-church/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 May 2017 03:01:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://egmontmika.com/blog/don%27t-go-to-church/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Church isn&amp;rsquo;t the same as a worship service.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nothing you &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;go to&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Neither a program nor an event. Far less a building, an organisation or a denomination. It wasn&amp;rsquo;t that from the beginning, and it still isn&amp;rsquo;t meant to be that today.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What is it, then?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s a family, a movement, a divine fellowship. A calling and a mission.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s what we are born into as followers of Jesus, redeemed through him, reconciled with our Father in heaven.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By his grace.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://molongnacua.com/being-church/?blogsub=confirmed#blog_subscription-3&#34;&gt;Molong Nacua&lt;/a&gt;, a Jesus follower from the Filipines, put it this way:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Church is where Christ lives, not the place where we meet. It is Christ-empowered people, a kingdom of priests for the purpose of winning against the works of the devil and establishing God&amp;rsquo;s Kingdom.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s about who we &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;are&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;. In Christ. Then follow him. Listen and obey. No matter where, no matter when - everywhere, at all times.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;go to&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; church. &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Be&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; church.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Coming Just a Little Earlier</title>
      <link>http://egmontmika.com/blog/just-a-little-earlier/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 May 2017 03:01:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://egmontmika.com/blog/just-a-little-earlier/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Some are late comers by habit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To them, it seems all right to always show up &amp;ldquo;just a little late&amp;rdquo;. Nobody will take notice anyway, it seems. And others will be late as well, they think.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To them, coming late is all right, as long as they don’t miss the highlights and as long as they get what they are expecting. And fulfill their social duty to show up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why invest more time than necessary?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In contrast, others may always want to come a little earlier. Be there before the program starts. Offering a little extra time. Just for being mentally prepared. Or for encouraging the host. Or for making themselves available. Like being able to lend a helping hand for the last preparations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Or for chatting with another early comer. Encourage someone who came with a need, with the desire to meet someone who would listen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Coming a little earlier gives you time to connect. Time to build a relationship. Time to care.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s precious time!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You may not want to miss it.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Taking Advantage of a Crisis</title>
      <link>http://egmontmika.com/blog/taking-advantage-of-a-crisis/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Apr 2017 03:01:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://egmontmika.com/blog/taking-advantage-of-a-crisis/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;You can hear an inspiring message. You can read a life-changing book.
You can get overwhelmed by a new insight.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yet, see nothing change.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For most of us, consuming such content just isn’t strong enough
to break through the habits and mental strongholds that we have built up over time.
Not strong enough to overcome our desire for comfort and to crack our fear.
We rather hold on to a lousy status-quo that makes us feel safe than take a step into the unknown.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is why a personal crisis can work as a door opener, but only if it
is stronger than our desire for comfort and stronger than our fear.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In order to move forward, good insights are just not good enough.
Probably we also need, from time to time, a period of destabilisation. That is, a real good crisis.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The secret of success is to accept the crisis and make it your friend. Take
 advantage of the insecurity that comes along with it, collect your strength and intentionally work for a break-through. This is the time to do it. Not waiting for the storm to calm down neither looking behind, but focussing on the future with decisiveness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For moving into a better future, a crisis can be inestimably valuable. Don&amp;rsquo;t let it become a stumbling block.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Instead, make it a stepping stone.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Investing</title>
      <link>http://egmontmika.com/blog/investing-in-the-future/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Apr 2017 03:01:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://egmontmika.com/blog/investing-in-the-future/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s never too late to invest in the future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The best time to plant a tree was twenty years ago, it is said.
Yet, the second best time is now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s never too late to plant a tree.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No matter how old you are, today you can start an education, start learning a language, start changeing a habit, start building a house, start a project&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today you can invest in your future. And in others&amp;rsquo;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our lives are far more significant than we tend to think at the moment. Every single one of us is the center of a sphere of influence. And we are reaching out, not only to the people around us during our own life time, but also to those who come after us.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They may not know who was the planter, yet they enjoy your tree and its fruit. And they may not always know who built that house or who started that project. Yet, they still enjoy its benefits.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today you can invest.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s never too late.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Cope with Short-Time Pressure</title>
      <link>http://egmontmika.com/blog/how-to-cope-with-short-time-pressure/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Mar 2017 03:01:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://egmontmika.com/blog/how-to-cope-with-short-time-pressure/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Just make this phone call&amp;hellip;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then prepare the dinner, pick up the kids, clean the house, buy a birthday present, fix the bike, get a haircut, wash the clothes, read the manual, answer the emails… The list seems endless.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How do you cope with short-time pressure?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The question is, what is &lt;em&gt;important&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;urgent&lt;/em&gt;? Not everything important is also urgent. And not everything urgent is also important. And some things that claim to be both are neither one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So let’s have a look at the four options and find out how to cope with them, one by one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Urgent &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; important. - Settle these things right away or as soon as possible.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Important, &lt;em&gt;but not&lt;/em&gt; urgent. - Schedule a time when you want to do this or reserve a fixed time every day, week or month. Then follow that schedule.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Urgent, &lt;em&gt;but not&lt;/em&gt; important. - Two options:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;a. Let someone else do it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;b. Don’t spoil your precious recreation or family time or your best working hours with that. Maybe you can do it while commuting or sitting in a waiting room or watching the news. Or when you are too tired for more important things.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Not urgent &lt;em&gt;and not&lt;/em&gt; important. - Two options:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;a. Never do it. And never let your mind get occupied with it. Don’t let junkmail lie around, but trash it right away.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;b. Write it on a seperate to-do-list for less important things and keep it there. Some matters get settled by themselves after a while. Then delete them. Or you settle them when they become urgent.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In order to make this work, you may want to make a deal with yourself and decide about your priorities. You can’t do all things at all times.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Clarify for yourself what your purpose is or your mission. What do you want to accomplish or improve or maximise? Why are you into this career? Who do you want to serve?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once you know your priorities, stay consistant and let them guide you. Then, confirm or renew your decision from time to time when not under pressure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This will keep short-time pressure away and get you where you want.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Time Savers</title>
      <link>http://egmontmika.com/blog/time-savers/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Mar 2017 22:44:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://egmontmika.com/blog/time-savers/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Time is limited. Time is precious. Time is running out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Life&lt;/em&gt; is running out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Civilisation, in turn, has blessed us with an abundance of time savers: dishwashers and washing machines, vacuum cleaners, lawn mowers, cars, airplanes, cellphones, computers…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Where does all the time go that we are constantly &amp;ldquo;saving&amp;rdquo;?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With calendars full to the brim, people seem to have less time than ever before. In order to meet with a friend, I may have to book an appointment several weeks ahead.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The truth is that none of us literally ”saves” any time. The amount of time we have stays always the same.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the contrary, many of these time savers may rather shorten our lives. We may seriously damage our health by eating too much time saving, processed foods or by doing too much time saving computer work. Not to mention the stress created by a time saving life style. Some of us shorten their lives drastically by getting killed during a time saving car trip….&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What all these time savers give us is not more time but more choice. More than ever before can we choose what to do with our time. Choose what is important. Do what is meaningful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Do what is right.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sadly enough, we often end up filling that time with even more time savers. More computer work and more car trips. Working for still more money which enables us to buy even more time savers&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What are your choices?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Letting Go</title>
      <link>http://egmontmika.com/blog/letting-go/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Feb 2017 03:01:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://egmontmika.com/blog/letting-go/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;No use to spend hours pondering on the past - regretting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You may say that you can learn from it. Yes, but any useful lesson from the past doesn’t take more than a few seconds, or maybe minutes. Anything
longer than that may become destructive. The past is gone and will
never come back.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In contrast, pondering on the future can be very rewarding.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The future gives you the opportunity to make a better decision, find a better solution, get better results, and avoid the old mistakes. The future is filled with possibilities and choices - good choices.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That is, if you first let go the past.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Did you let go?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can start your future right away - by letting go and pondering on the future. Admitted, the actual work still needs to be done.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yet, it&amp;rsquo;s a good start.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Comments&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Anonym&lt;/em&gt; Hej Egmont, tack för dagens inlägg, stämmer så väl, det är så lätt att fastna i det negativa man varit med om och ge det alldeles för mycket tid. Vi får kasta oss på Gud som verkligen känner till alla detaljer i våra liv och vill att vi ska bli stilla och lyssna in vad han vill säga oss. Uppskattar din blogg som har en enkelhet samtidigt som den är djup.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Radical Edge</title>
      <link>http://egmontmika.com/blog/the-radical-edge/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Feb 2017 03:01:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://egmontmika.com/blog/the-radical-edge/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Growing spiritual movements often have a radical edge.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Their followers are filled with a vision and strongly committed to their mission. They gladly step out of
their comfort zone, take great risks, are willing to sacrifice, and work day and night,
paying the price in order to fulfill that mission.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first followers of Jesus became such a movement. And today they still are, that is, wherever they
genuinely follow Jesus.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, large chunks of this movement became and still become watered-down over time, loosing their
radicality and their edge. Thinking they have been too radical, too zealous, too different from the world
 around them, they may feel the need to become more “normal”, regarded ”decent”, more like everybody else.
 Trying to fit in, playing it safe.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Getting established.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This results in the loss of passion and mission. And the loss of life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, all that remains is a skeleton — an institutional framework with its positions, procedures, rituals
and traditions, yet, without the faith and the spiritual power that once made them grow and change their world.
The  machinery still runs idle for a while and may survive several generations. However, its life is
constantly declining and finally coming to an end.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Followers of Jesus have no obligation to follow such a development, even less to contribute to it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today, Jesus is more present and active in this world than ever before since the early days, and by his Spirit
he constantly moves on, pouring out his life into ever more people, creating ever more ways to fulfill his
mission - to seek and save the lost.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With a radical edge, through his followers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Through people like you and me.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ready to Engage</title>
      <link>http://egmontmika.com/blog/ready-to-engage/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Feb 2017 03:01:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://egmontmika.com/blog/ready-to-engage/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Everyday you can choose your attitude.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For instance, the attitude of being ready. Ready to engage to the
benefit of others.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ready to help&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ready to find a solution&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ready to change things to the better&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ready to give hope&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ready to trust&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Probably,  nothing of all that is quite natural to anyone of us. Yet, we can work on it.
Day by day, week after week. Sooner or later, this attitude will become so much part of your
personality you don’t need to remind yourself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At that point, it’s no big deal anymore. Not for you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yet, others get encouraged.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And you satisfied.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Love Versus Fear</title>
      <link>http://egmontmika.com/blog/love-overcomes-fear/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2017 22:44:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://egmontmika.com/blog/love-overcomes-fear/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Love and fear don&amp;rsquo;t match.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One primary characteristic of virtually all religious systems around the world is fear:
fear of judgment, fear of curses, fear of hell, fear of punishment, fear of failing - communicated and
held up by some sort of religious authority or system.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sadly, this also can be found within Christianity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In contrast, read the following:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;There is no fear in love. But perfect love drives out fear, because fear has to do
with punishment. The one who fears is not made perfect in love.&amp;rdquo; (1 John 4:18 NIV)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Whoever does not love does not know God, because God is love.&amp;rdquo; (1 John 4:8 NIV) &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;So do not fear, for I am with you; do not be dismayed, for I am your God. I will
strengthen you and help you; I will uphold you with my righteous right hand.&amp;rdquo;
(Isaiah 41:10 NIV)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Spirit of Jesus and the spirit of fear are opposed to each other.
The Spirit of Jesus produces love that overcomes fear.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Having said this, here comes the delicate question:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If love makes us strong and able to overcome fear, what does that insight teach us for the art of raising children? Can there be any place for frightening or threatening a child in good pedagogics?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Comments&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Sid&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That is a very good question. I wonder what the spanking camp would have to say about that. I remember being pro-spanking, as that was how I was raised and believed how one raised children. I would never say my parents did not love me, but the practice that was culturally and socially accepted did create a lot of emotional damage. For them, &amp;lsquo;sparing the rod and spoiling the child&amp;rsquo; held greater bearance. I assume this is what you are referring to?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Egmont&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yes, Sid. Although, I am aware that I will not be able to change any of the deeply rooted convictions in that direction. In Western Europe, this more extreme position that you describe is not so common among young parents, but I believe that there are all kinds of weaker variations still in use. And many a parent may despise these practices, but still slide into such a behavior, not willingly, but as an emergency reaction. This heritage is often deeper rooted inside of us as a pattern of behavior and thought than we want to acknowledge. And to get out of it requires an amount of effort over a long time.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Fruit of Your Life</title>
      <link>http://egmontmika.com/blog/the-fruit-of-your-life/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Dec 2016 22:44:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://egmontmika.com/blog/the-fruit-of-your-life/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;All we have is each other.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s all we’ve ever had of real value, and all we’re ever going to get. Neither less, nor more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s neither your career nor your possessions, power, image or self-esteem. Neither your consumption nor
sparetime activities, nor your opinions and ideas. And it’s not your doctrines.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ultimately, people are all that matters, and your relationships all that counts. They are the substance of your
efforts and your time investments, worth everything.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The fruit of your life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s up to you how much fruit there is and will be.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It all depends on how you engage with people and on the qualities you build into your relationships.
Also, on the outcome of your interactions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Are they uplifting or destructive? Reinforcing life or weakening life? Are you a giver or a taker?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s up to you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Heart Decision</title>
      <link>http://egmontmika.com/blog/a-heart-decision/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Dec 2016 22:44:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://egmontmika.com/blog/a-heart-decision/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;You can’t argue a person into Heaven.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In spiritual matters arguing is futile. Even worse, it’s counterproductive.
Each argument will provoke at least one counter-argument, supplying your opponent
with still another brick for his defense wall.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Arguing presumes that we can use force of will to change minds - and souls.
Yet, force begets counterforce. And what would be the benefit of winning an
argument, anyway? Probably you&amp;rsquo;d produce another wisenheimer, (one just like you and me, in this case).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is a better way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The path forward, it seems, is to connect, to engage and to serve. To teach patiently and
earn credibility by living what you teach. To build trust. Then, inviting the other person to join you in
your journey.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, this seldom happens overnight. It takes time and commitment and humility. And honest
concern for the other person.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Becoming a disciple of Jesus starts with a free and trusting decision from within.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A heart decision.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Start a Church</title>
      <link>http://egmontmika.com/blog/how-to-start-a-church-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Nov 2016 03:01:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://egmontmika.com/blog/how-to-start-a-church-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It’s easy to imagine that the only way to start a church is by:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Renting an auditorium,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Engaging a speaker and a worship team,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Gathering a crowd.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yet, there is another way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You don’t need all of this, not even money. Instead of starting an organisation with a program, you could ignite a process of disciple making. And you can do this right where you are, wherever you live, work, study or spend your spare time. You start out by making just one disciple of Jesus. And then another one, and another. One or two at a time, sometimes even a couple or a family.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And by demonstrating and being an example, you teach these people to do the same with their relatives and friends.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your home base is your kitchen table. This is where you gather, share your meals, pray, teach, mentor and empower those who want to join you. This is where everything starts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your area of operation is your social network, your family, relatives, friends and colleagues. Then the city, its streets and squares, the parks, shopping centers, restaurants and cafés, the gyms and clubs… any place where you can meet people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sooner or later, there will be a fellowship of Jesus-followers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is church.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It may seem a lot easier, faster and more rewarding way to rent an auditorium, engage a speaker and a worship team and make enough noise to attract a crowd, then call it a “church”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The question is, what Jesus would call it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And - how would he do it?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Taking a New Decision</title>
      <link>http://egmontmika.com/blog/taking-a-new-decision/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Nov 2016 03:01:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://egmontmika.com/blog/taking-a-new-decision/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Sometimes it&amp;rsquo;s time for a change.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From time to time, following Jesus requires a new decision.
Why can it be so hard to take that decision?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Would it mean that your former decisions, traditions and habits, your arguments,
convictions and priorities become meaningless?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Would it mean that &lt;em&gt;all&lt;/em&gt; was wrong?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not necessarily. Probably, it all was right, based on the
information you had at that time. But now you know more. Now you have a
better understanding.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now you feel the need for a change.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, what will you do?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Will you let your tradition or habit or convenience be strong enough to override your desire
for a new and better decision?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Or will you give in to peer pressure of sticking with
your &amp;ldquo;tribe&amp;rdquo;, your relatives and friends or your group (&amp;ldquo;What will they say?&amp;rdquo;)?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sometimes, it takes humility and courage to make a new decision.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And trust in the voice of your heart.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Comments&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Noomi&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Or be afraid that people won&amp;rsquo;t take you serious because you&amp;rsquo;re not sticking to what
you built up and believed in and instead run off to something new and often more uncertain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Egmont&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;True. If you need much confirmation you better stay inside
the box.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Kristina&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yes, sometimes God invites you to leave everything. We lived in the big city for about 10 years and have been the leaders of a small home church. However, we felt the need to leave it all and move into a small village with just a few people around. Hard to understand such a decision! But we feel so so happy and God already gave us a new church family with really honest and worm people who accepted us so lovingly. Change is good if it is led by God. Sometimes we feel like God already prepared and arranged things in advance and we just go and find it all arranged and set out waiting for us. He is such a provider!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Egmont&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hi Kristina!
Thank you for your comment. This sounds so right and good. Peace and joy follow those who are being led by the Spirit, no matter what the circumstances. And whenever the situation does not look so great, the family of the Lord stands out even greater. Making one or a few disciples, one by one, who can do the same with other people is the best we can do. No church program can ever match up to that. It’s quality that counts in the Kingdom, not numbers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Kristina&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Amen, thank you for your encouragement.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>