<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blogs on Egmont Mika</title>
    <link>http://egmontmika.com/blog/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blogs on Egmont Mika</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 11 Nov 2020 03:01:45 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://egmontmika.com/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>New Book - Turning Missional</title>
      <link>http://egmontmika.com/blog/turning-missional-book/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Nov 2020 03:01:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://egmontmika.com/blog/turning-missional-book/</guid>
      <description>Hi friends!
It&amp;rsquo;s been a while since I published my last post on this blog. Here is what happened:
During the process of writing I increasingly came to the conviction that I should write a book with only one narrow, unique focus. It&amp;rsquo;s the question, How can we as churchgoers become missional disciples of Jesus? How can we step beyond church programmes and on a personal level start living an everyday missional life?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Request</title>
      <link>http://egmontmika.com/blog/request/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Apr 2018 06:39:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://egmontmika.com/blog/request/</guid>
      <description>Hello friends!
This week I&amp;rsquo;m asking you for a favour.
Is there anyone among the readers of my blog who in these days is making one or several disciples? Or contributing to it? Disciples of Jesus according to his commission (Mt 28:18-20)?
I’ll be excited to hear from you. Please, write a few lines into the comment box below and tell me in short what you are doing and how you are doing it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Who Is the Master of Your Mind?</title>
      <link>http://egmontmika.com/blog/who-is-the-master-of-your-mind/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Apr 2018 06:39:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://egmontmika.com/blog/who-is-the-master-of-your-mind/</guid>
      <description>Advertisements, email marketing, news, gossip, tv shows, facebook, iTube, magazines…
The world is cluttered and filled with millions of distractions, trying to catch your attention and fill your day.
  Keeping you from doing your work.
  Keeping you from getting your sleep.
  Nebulizing your focus and your calling.
  It’s not your fault that these things are around, and it’s not your responsibility to change that.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Life and Death in Your Hands</title>
      <link>http://egmontmika.com/blog/life-and-death/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Apr 2018 22:44:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://egmontmika.com/blog/life-and-death/</guid>
      <description>You can’t save the whole world.
However, there is at least one for whom you can make all the difference. The difference between life and death.
There is a well-known story about a man, who on his morning walk along the beach watches a boy picking up starfishes and throwing them back into the water. When asked about his doing the boy replied, I’m saving starfishes. If they stay on the beach, they will die.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hopeless?</title>
      <link>http://egmontmika.com/blog/hopeless/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Mar 2018 22:44:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://egmontmika.com/blog/hopeless/</guid>
      <description>Some people seem never to learn.
They leave their crumbs on the table, put their dirty coffee cup in the sink, spit their chewing gum on top, and just don’t see - and smell - that the trash is overflowing.
Don’t they know any better?
If this were the case, the solution would be to inform them and show them how to finish a coffee break properly.
However, not knowing rarely is the reason.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Overcoming Bitterness</title>
      <link>http://egmontmika.com/blog/overcoming-bitterness/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Feb 2018 03:01:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://egmontmika.com/blog/overcoming-bitterness/</guid>
      <description>Bitterness is a killer.
Holding onto accusations hurts you more than anything else. Leaves you with a far greater damage than anything people can do to you. Bitterness steals your peace and breaks you down continuously. It kills you not only emotionally and spiritually, but also physically.
So, what can you do in order to overcome? Here follow three steps:
Step 1
The first step is to stop.
Stop meditating on what happened.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Power of a Story</title>
      <link>http://egmontmika.com/blog/the-power-of-a-story/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Feb 2018 03:01:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://egmontmika.com/blog/the-power-of-a-story/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;In the beginning, God created&amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo;
This is how the probably most significant story of humanity begins. People have told this story for thousands of years, and it still is passed on from generation to generation.
It’s the story of stories.
This story tells us where we come from and what our purpose is, and it connects us humans globally, across the borders of races, nations, and generations.
It’s the story that tells us who we are.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Art of Enjoying the Uncomfortable</title>
      <link>http://egmontmika.com/blog/the-art-of-enjoying-the-uncomfortable/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Jan 2018 03:01:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://egmontmika.com/blog/the-art-of-enjoying-the-uncomfortable/</guid>
      <description>Progress and comfort don’t match.
While not everything that is uncomfortable automatically will give you progress, there will always be a certain amount of inconvenience going along with it.
Performance spikes when we’re doing something out of our norm.
This is not only true for sports but probably for all areas of life, for instance, our spiritual life.
Throughout Scripture, we find that following God’s call and striving for a comfortable life seem to contradict each other.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Three Steps to Overcome Worrying</title>
      <link>http://egmontmika.com/blog/three-steps-to-overcome-worrying/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jan 2018 03:01:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://egmontmika.com/blog/three-steps-to-overcome-worrying/</guid>
      <description>Worrying is NOT a virtue.
On the contrary, it’s absolutely destructive. It’s a poison.
Worrying obscures your faith, weakens your strength, takes away your initiative, and quenches your creativity.
It steals your joy.
Worrying breaks you down spiritually, mentally, and physically. And it keeps you from doing your work.
It keeps you from living your life.
It’s easy to make people and circumstances responsible for your worries. Yet, they are not the producers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reconsidering Church</title>
      <link>http://egmontmika.com/blog/reconsidering_church/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Dec 2017 03:01:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://egmontmika.com/blog/reconsidering_church/</guid>
      <description>The status quo of the institutionalized church is powerful indeed.
And we try to keep it alive by small improvements here and there, fancier equipment, trendier arrangements, and popular speakers. We add layers, patches, and small improvisations. Try to be modern.
All to save something we don&amp;rsquo;t want to reconsider.
We hardly ever question its basic structure, i. e., the institutional system, including constitutions, elections, offices, fundraising, buildings, and programs. Its division into clergy/professionals and laity.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Your Ways and His Ways</title>
      <link>http://egmontmika.com/blog/his-ways/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Dec 2017 03:01:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://egmontmika.com/blog/his-ways/</guid>
      <description>When you pray, who does most of the talking?
You or the Lord?
Your answer will depend on where your focus is. Whether it is on yourself and your problems and desires, or on Him and His concerns.
On your ways or on His.
Depending on your focus you mostly either talk or listen.
God is looking for people who are eager to listen.
He wants you to hear what He has to say and what He wants to do.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Controversial.</title>
      <link>http://egmontmika.com/blog/controversial/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Nov 2017 03:01:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://egmontmika.com/blog/controversial/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s not a bad thing to be controversial.
And it’s absolutely no sin.
Anyone who stands up for what is right will meet opposition. The higher your position, the worse it can get. The stronger the rejection and the more disastrous the possible consequences.
The higher your purpose, the higher the cost.
With this in mind, it seems an easier way to adapt, to conform and be nice, trying to please as many as possible.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stand Up - Speak Up - Take Action!</title>
      <link>http://egmontmika.com/blog/what-do-you-stand-up-for/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Nov 2017 06:39:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://egmontmika.com/blog/what-do-you-stand-up-for/</guid>
      <description>Have you experienced this?
You know exactly what would be the right thing to do. Right now, you could change a situation for the better. Help someone, improve an organization, or turn a hopeless situation.
Yet, you hesitate.
Why do you back off?
Is it because of convenience? Or complacency? Or doubt?
Or because of the fear of being taken advantage of? Or because of possible risks? The fear of failure?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Your Valuable Life</title>
      <link>http://egmontmika.com/blog/your-valuable-life2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Oct 2017 03:01:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://egmontmika.com/blog/your-valuable-life2/</guid>
      <description>Life&amp;rsquo;s value is not defined by its highlights.
Sunday worship services may leave the impression that living the Christian life is a series of elegant meetings. Jumping from celebration to celebration. Like a butterfly, from flower to flower. Looking for the next sensation, the next spiritual experience. With lots of smiles.
Nothing could be more wrong than that.
Rather, it’s the other way around. Your valuable life is the life you live in between the highlights.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Power of Long-Term Commitment</title>
      <link>http://egmontmika.com/blog/the-power-of-commitment/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2017 03:01:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://egmontmika.com/blog/the-power-of-commitment/</guid>
      <description>Have you ever had a great idea? And tried to make it work?
Tried to change something to the better? To accomplish something important and really worth the effort? Something that would improve your life and the world around you significantly?
Have you tried - and failed?
It’s easy to blame the opposition or people’s ignorance or the circumstances. Or the bureaucracy or the system…
It’s easy to blame and give up.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What Are You Waiting For?</title>
      <link>http://egmontmika.com/blog/what-are-you-waiting-for/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Sep 2017 03:01:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://egmontmika.com/blog/what-are-you-waiting-for/</guid>
      <description>Are you ready to make a disciple?
In case your answer is &amp;ldquo;no&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;not yet&amp;rdquo;, what would you still need?
Jesus trained his disciples for only three and a half years, then sent them out.
Where they fully educated then? - No.
Did they master the skills of an evangelist or preacher or teacher? - Probably not.
In fact, they hardly had the faith necessary, nor the skill, nor the understanding.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Many Sermons Do You Need?</title>
      <link>http://egmontmika.com/blog/how-many-sermons/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Sep 2017 03:01:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://egmontmika.com/blog/how-many-sermons/</guid>
      <description>How many sermons do you need in order to become a disciple?
Probably one.
Or maybe a few. The rest is modelling.
Yet, modelling is not done from the pulpit, but in everyday life. By sharing experiences, communicating kingdom values, demonstrating these values and explaining the hows and whys. Learning to listen to the Spirit and then follow.
By taking action.
Admitted, preparation can take a life time. There will always be something more to learn, more to understand and more to prepare.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Church and Money</title>
      <link>http://egmontmika.com/blog/church-and-money/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Aug 2017 03:01:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://egmontmika.com/blog/church-and-money/</guid>
      <description>”It’s all about money!”
This is what we hear the critics say, while pointing at the large amounts of money collected by Christian ministries today.
”No, it’s not true”, we answer, believing to have a better understanding. ”It’s all about Jesus and the Good News and about saving people for eternity. It’s about mission. Of course, this costs money. The more money we give, the more people we can reach.”</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building a Fortune</title>
      <link>http://egmontmika.com/blog/building-a-fortune/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jun 2017 03:01:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://egmontmika.com/blog/building-a-fortune/</guid>
      <description>You can’t buy trust.
Yet, it’s one of the greatest assets you can have. It’s a fortune.
At first glance, building trust seems simple. You say what you are going to do and then do what you said. You keep your promises. You act out your words. Never giving less, rather a little more.
Without any hidden agenda, without cutting corners. Without faking the results. And without covering up your mistakes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Don&#39;t Go to Church!</title>
      <link>http://egmontmika.com/blog/dont-go-to-church/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 May 2017 03:01:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://egmontmika.com/blog/dont-go-to-church/</guid>
      <description>Church isn&amp;rsquo;t the same as a worship service.
Nothing you go to.
Neither a program nor an event. Far less a building, an organisation or a denomination. It wasn&amp;rsquo;t that from the beginning, and it still isn&amp;rsquo;t meant to be that today.
What is it, then?
It’s a family, a movement, a divine fellowship. A calling and a mission.
It’s what we are born into as followers of Jesus, redeemed through him, reconciled with our Father in heaven.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Coming Just a Little Earlier</title>
      <link>http://egmontmika.com/blog/just-a-little-earlier/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 May 2017 03:01:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://egmontmika.com/blog/just-a-little-earlier/</guid>
      <description>Some are late comers by habit.
To them, it seems all right to always show up &amp;ldquo;just a little late&amp;rdquo;. Nobody will take notice anyway, it seems. And others will be late as well, they think.
To them, coming late is all right, as long as they don’t miss the highlights and as long as they get what they are expecting. And fulfill their social duty to show up.
Why invest more time than necessary?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Taking Advantage of a Crisis</title>
      <link>http://egmontmika.com/blog/taking-advantage-of-a-crisis/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Apr 2017 03:01:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://egmontmika.com/blog/taking-advantage-of-a-crisis/</guid>
      <description>You can hear an inspiring message. You can read a life-changing book. You can get overwhelmed by a new insight.
Yet, see nothing change.
For most of us, consuming such content just isn’t strong enough to break through the habits and mental strongholds that we have built up over time. Not strong enough to overcome our desire for comfort and to crack our fear. We rather hold on to a lousy status-quo that makes us feel safe than take a step into the unknown.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Investing</title>
      <link>http://egmontmika.com/blog/investing-in-the-future/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Apr 2017 03:01:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://egmontmika.com/blog/investing-in-the-future/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s never too late to invest in the future.
The best time to plant a tree was twenty years ago, it is said. Yet, the second best time is now.
It’s never too late to plant a tree.
No matter how old you are, today you can start an education, start learning a language, start changeing a habit, start building a house, start a project&amp;hellip;
Today you can invest in your future.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Cope with Short-Time Pressure</title>
      <link>http://egmontmika.com/blog/how-to-cope-with-short-time-pressure/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Mar 2017 03:01:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://egmontmika.com/blog/how-to-cope-with-short-time-pressure/</guid>
      <description>Just make this phone call&amp;hellip;.
Then prepare the dinner, pick up the kids, clean the house, buy a birthday present, fix the bike, get a haircut, wash the clothes, read the manual, answer the emails… The list seems endless.
How do you cope with short-time pressure?
The question is, what is important and urgent? Not everything important is also urgent. And not everything urgent is also important. And some things that claim to be both are neither one.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Time Savers</title>
      <link>http://egmontmika.com/blog/time-savers/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Mar 2017 22:44:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://egmontmika.com/blog/time-savers/</guid>
      <description>Time is limited. Time is precious. Time is running out.
Life is running out.
Civilisation, in turn, has blessed us with an abundance of time savers: dishwashers and washing machines, vacuum cleaners, lawn mowers, cars, airplanes, cellphones, computers…
Where does all the time go that we are constantly &amp;ldquo;saving&amp;rdquo;?
With calendars full to the brim, people seem to have less time than ever before. In order to meet with a friend, I may have to book an appointment several weeks ahead.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Letting Go</title>
      <link>http://egmontmika.com/blog/letting-go/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Feb 2017 03:01:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://egmontmika.com/blog/letting-go/</guid>
      <description>No use to spend hours pondering on the past - regretting.
You may say that you can learn from it. Yes, but any useful lesson from the past doesn’t take more than a few seconds, or maybe minutes. Anything longer than that may become destructive. The past is gone and will never come back.
In contrast, pondering on the future can be very rewarding.
The future gives you the opportunity to make a better decision, find a better solution, get better results, and avoid the old mistakes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Radical Edge</title>
      <link>http://egmontmika.com/blog/the-radical-edge/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Feb 2017 03:01:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://egmontmika.com/blog/the-radical-edge/</guid>
      <description>Growing spiritual movements often have a radical edge.
Their followers are filled with a vision and strongly committed to their mission. They gladly step out of their comfort zone, take great risks, are willing to sacrifice, and work day and night, paying the price in order to fulfill that mission.
The first followers of Jesus became such a movement. And today they still are, that is, wherever they genuinely follow Jesus.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ready to Engage</title>
      <link>http://egmontmika.com/blog/ready-to-engage/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Feb 2017 03:01:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://egmontmika.com/blog/ready-to-engage/</guid>
      <description>Everyday you can choose your attitude.
For instance, the attitude of being ready. Ready to engage to the benefit of others.
 Ready to help Ready to find a solution Ready to change things to the better Ready to give hope Ready to trust  Probably, nothing of all that is quite natural to anyone of us. Yet, we can work on it. Day by day, week after week. Sooner or later, this attitude will become so much part of your personality you don’t need to remind yourself.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Love Versus Fear</title>
      <link>http://egmontmika.com/blog/love-overcomes-fear/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2017 22:44:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://egmontmika.com/blog/love-overcomes-fear/</guid>
      <description>Love and fear don&amp;rsquo;t match.
One primary characteristic of virtually all religious systems around the world is fear: fear of judgment, fear of curses, fear of hell, fear of punishment, fear of failing - communicated and held up by some sort of religious authority or system.
Sadly, this also can be found within Christianity.
In contrast, read the following:
  &amp;ldquo;There is no fear in love. But perfect love drives out fear, because fear has to do with punishment.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Fruit of Your Life</title>
      <link>http://egmontmika.com/blog/the-fruit-of-your-life/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Dec 2016 22:44:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://egmontmika.com/blog/the-fruit-of-your-life/</guid>
      <description>All we have is each other.
It&amp;rsquo;s all we’ve ever had of real value, and all we’re ever going to get. Neither less, nor more.
It’s neither your career nor your possessions, power, image or self-esteem. Neither your consumption nor sparetime activities, nor your opinions and ideas. And it’s not your doctrines.
Ultimately, people are all that matters, and your relationships all that counts. They are the substance of your efforts and your time investments, worth everything.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Heart Decision</title>
      <link>http://egmontmika.com/blog/a-heart-decision/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Dec 2016 22:44:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://egmontmika.com/blog/a-heart-decision/</guid>
      <description>You can’t argue a person into Heaven.
In spiritual matters arguing is futile. Even worse, it’s counterproductive. Each argument will provoke at least one counter-argument, supplying your opponent with still another brick for his defense wall.
Arguing presumes that we can use force of will to change minds - and souls. Yet, force begets counterforce. And what would be the benefit of winning an argument, anyway? Probably you&amp;rsquo;d produce another wisenheimer, (one just like you and me, in this case).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Start a Church</title>
      <link>http://egmontmika.com/blog/how-to-start-a-church-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Nov 2016 03:01:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://egmontmika.com/blog/how-to-start-a-church-2/</guid>
      <description>It’s easy to imagine that the only way to start a church is by:
 Renting an auditorium, Engaging a speaker and a worship team, Gathering a crowd.  Yet, there is another way.
You don’t need all of this, not even money. Instead of starting an organisation with a program, you could ignite a process of disciple making. And you can do this right where you are, wherever you live, work, study or spend your spare time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Taking a New Decision</title>
      <link>http://egmontmika.com/blog/taking-a-new-decision/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Nov 2016 03:01:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://egmontmika.com/blog/taking-a-new-decision/</guid>
      <description>Sometimes it&amp;rsquo;s time for a change.
From time to time, following Jesus requires a new decision. Why can it be so hard to take that decision?
Would it mean that your former decisions, traditions and habits, your arguments, convictions and priorities become meaningless?
Would it mean that all was wrong?
Not necessarily. Probably, it all was right, based on the information you had at that time. But now you know more.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Broken Trust</title>
      <link>http://egmontmika.com/blog/broken-trust-8/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Oct 2016 13:58:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://egmontmika.com/blog/broken-trust-8/</guid>
      <description>Broken trust is painful.
People can be wonderful, but also give you a nightmare. Loving people includes the risk of getting hurt. The more you love, the more vulnerable you get, the more pain you may have to suffer.
Worst of all, the suffering of broken trust. Suffering a life-long injury.
Therefore, if you want to play safe, don’t get engaged with people. Don’t love, don’t care. Keep out of reach.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Impact of Your Influence</title>
      <link>http://egmontmika.com/blog/the-impact-of-your-influence/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Oct 2016 03:01:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://egmontmika.com/blog/the-impact-of-your-influence/</guid>
      <description>You can change things to the better.
The trust you give, the joy you share, the love you invest, the help you give, the standard you set, the problem you solve, the wisdom you share… have the potential to change things to the better, to become a blessing to you and others.
Moving people foreward.
Causing someone to pick up what you did and act in a similar way, and again, change things to the better, for even more people.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What Really Matters - Part 3</title>
      <link>http://egmontmika.com/blog/what-really-matters-part-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Sep 2016 06:39:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://egmontmika.com/blog/what-really-matters-part-3/</guid>
      <description>You are a follower of Jesus? In this case, you might be interested in the question,
What matters to Jesus?
Jesus himself said, it’s the glory of his Father in Heaven. To honor Him and to carry out His will. How did he do this?
By loving people.
For Jesus, this meant sharing his life and giving his life.
Today, the Father is about to prepare humanity for eternity by building His universal family.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What Really Matters - Part 2</title>
      <link>http://egmontmika.com/blog/what-really-matters-part-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Sep 2016 03:01:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://egmontmika.com/blog/what-really-matters-part-2/</guid>
      <description>You can thrive your career, acquire wealth and reputation, even experience tremendous impact in your ministry. Yet, if your relationships are poor&amp;hellip;
Then nothing else matters.
Investing in people is the best you can ever do.
Giving your time and efforts or whatever you have, ultimately giving your love.
Love is the only currency with eternal value. And its value increases the more you give.
Like any other investment, though, love investments include risks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What Really Matters - Part 1</title>
      <link>http://egmontmika.com/blog/what-really-matters/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2016 03:01:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://egmontmika.com/blog/what-really-matters/</guid>
      <description>Most probably, it’s not the public opinion.
And not what everybody is talking about right now at the coffee table.
Like today’s hottest news or sensation or scandal, created by the media. Or this season’s trendiest fashion or coolest design or latest ”must have”, launched by the market. And it&amp;rsquo;s certainly not the score of last night’s soccer game.
What really matters is probably not whatever tries to steal your attention right now.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Better than a Thrill</title>
      <link>http://egmontmika.com/blog/better-than-a-thrill2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Aug 2016 03:01:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://egmontmika.com/blog/better-than-a-thrill2/</guid>
      <description>Are you looking for a thrill? Something really exciting?
You might have been excited when you experienced the Lord for the first time, or when you got baptized in the Spirit and started speaking in tongues, or when you for the first time prayed for someone and this person actually got healed on the spot. Or maybe when you sensed the Lord’s presence during a special worship service… That, if anything, is really exciting!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Time for a Break</title>
      <link>http://egmontmika.com/blog/time-for-a-break/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jun 2016 06:39:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://egmontmika.com/blog/time-for-a-break/</guid>
      <description>In Sweden, summer has arrived and it’s time to take a break.
For Åsa and me, this means to close down all of our regular activities and, except eating and sleeping, do other things than we usually do.
That’s what we call ”to rest”.
Like traveling both short and long distances to visit friends and relatives, staying for a while in Munich, my home city, hiking in the Alps and, last not least, discovering new places.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Don&#39;t Let the Sermon Fail!</title>
      <link>http://egmontmika.com/blog/dont-let-the-sermon-fail/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jun 2016 03:01:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://egmontmika.com/blog/dont-let-the-sermon-fail/</guid>
      <description>Have you ever tried to change someone’s habit without success? You kept arguing, but it just didn&amp;rsquo;t help?
We probably change a habit on other grounds than logical thinking. Real change is made on a much deeper, emotional or maybe even spiritual level. It’s the level where we manage things like courage and fear, trust and distrust, faith and doubt.
It seems to me like most of us, most of the time are not really ready for a change.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Removing the Mask</title>
      <link>http://egmontmika.com/blog/removing-the-mask/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 May 2016 03:01:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://egmontmika.com/blog/removing-the-mask/</guid>
      <description>He was a pastor. A gifted preacher and brilliant Bible school teacher, respected and loved by his church and his large family, particularly known and appreciated for his books and seminars on family relationships.
Then the unexpected happened.
In short, one day he left his wife and family, quit his ministry and moved to a far away country in order to start all over again, leaving his family, co-workers and church members behind in shock.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How &#39;Stable&#39; Shall We Be?</title>
      <link>http://egmontmika.com/blog/is-your-church-stable/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 May 2016 06:39:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://egmontmika.com/blog/is-your-church-stable/</guid>
      <description>One significant characteristic of any organization is the pursuit of stability. The same is true for churches and home groups.
Stability gives us a sense of security, peace and success. The turbulent times of initial struggles are over and we finally arrived at a place where we can lean back and enjoy our accomplishments. Now, we are established and we finally have been accepted by our surroundings. And we know how to run this church.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Numbers, Numbers, Numbers!</title>
      <link>http://egmontmika.com/blog/numbers-numbers/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Apr 2016 03:01:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://egmontmika.com/blog/numbers-numbers/</guid>
      <description>Church leaders tend to be highly interested in numbers.
Typically, they ask questions like, How many members does the church have, how high is the weekly attendance and how much did the offering bring? And they want to know how these numbers develop from week to week, month to month and year to year.
Admitted, statistics are useful. They enable us to measure and to compare, to set up goals and to stay focussed, and they make us feel successful whenever numbers go up.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stuff or People?</title>
      <link>http://egmontmika.com/blog/stuff-or-people/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Apr 2016 03:01:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://egmontmika.com/blog/stuff-or-people/</guid>
      <description>Imagine someone handed you 10.000 USD to spend on whatever you want. The only condition would be that you had to spend it right away, on the same day.
What would you do with the money?
Maybe your mind would go to that fancy computer you had been eying at for a long time. Or that cool hifi-system, or the latest version of your favorite cellphone, or a diving gear for you next dream vacation, or this trendy leather jacket?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Honest and Joyful</title>
      <link>http://egmontmika.com/blog/honest-and-joyful/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2016 03:01:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://egmontmika.com/blog/honest-and-joyful/</guid>
      <description>Meeting people is exciting.
It’s always exciting to listen to someone’s story. Everyone has a story worth listening to and learning from, as long as they are honest and their story is true. And it’s exciting and worth both time and effort to get engaged with people who are honest about themselves and about what they do. Free from pretending.
You can learn from those conversations, widen your knowledge and understanding, getting inspired.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Two Ways to Benefit from Your Enemies</title>
      <link>http://egmontmika.com/blog/two-ways-to-benefit-from-your-enemies/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Mar 2016 06:59:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://egmontmika.com/blog/two-ways-to-benefit-from-your-enemies/</guid>
      <description>You can benefit from your enemies.
Indeed, you not only benefit from your families, relatives and friends and all who love you, but you can also benefit from your enemies, from those who oppose you, bother you, despise you, hate you, treat you badly.
If you understand this, you can turn those negative relationships into an asset.
This doesn’t mean that you intentionally will have to make enemies or give people reason to hate you.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Trust Decision</title>
      <link>http://egmontmika.com/blog/a-trust-decision/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Mar 2016 06:39:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://egmontmika.com/blog/a-trust-decision/</guid>
      <description>Discipleship is a decision.
You don’t just slide into being a disciple of Jesus by accident. Or wake up one morning and find yourself having arrived there.
It always requires a conscious decision on your behalf - your own personal decision.
Neither your father nor mother, nor your buddies can do that for you. Nobody else can, but you. You don&amp;rsquo;t have to wait for anyone&amp;rsquo;s agreement, nor is there anyone else to blame for not taking that decision.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Destructive Faith</title>
      <link>http://egmontmika.com/blog/destructive-faith/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Feb 2016 03:01:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://egmontmika.com/blog/destructive-faith/</guid>
      <description>Destruction doesn’t always have a negative connotation. Many times it is an absolutely necessary part of the creative process.
Farm lands are created by tearing down trees, better neighborhoods from slums, new life from destructive habits. They all go through destructive processes before something new could be created. Sometimes, new life does not appear unless and until the old has been torn down. It’s not always possible nor is it safe to be building on top of the old.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Does Jesus Lead You?</title>
      <link>http://egmontmika.com/blog/how-does-jesus-lead-you/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Feb 2016 03:01:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://egmontmika.com/blog/how-does-jesus-lead-you/</guid>
      <description>So, you are a follower of Jesus?
He is your Lord and Master? And your Teacher? Then, what exactly does he teach you?
No, I am not asking you what you know about him, like when and where he lived, what he did and what he said. Neither am I asking about the doctrines or morals, or whatever your church teaches about him.
What I’m asking is, How does he impact you?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Much Are Your Ideas Worth?</title>
      <link>http://egmontmika.com/blog/how-much-worth-are-your-ideas/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Jan 2016 06:39:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://egmontmika.com/blog/how-much-worth-are-your-ideas/</guid>
      <description>Great ideas are fun!
Great ideas sound good and make you feel good. Great ideas always find their listeners.
However, an idea is quite irrelevant as long as it isn’t tested.
The testing makes all the difference. It separates the achiever from the mere dreamer. The testing is the real hard part.
Probably, one thing the testing shows is that your great idea isn’t really that great. Others had the same idea before you and didn’t find it worth the trouble to make it work out.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Much Is Half a Promise Worth?</title>
      <link>http://egmontmika.com/blog/how-much-worth-is-half-a-promise/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Jan 2016 03:01:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://egmontmika.com/blog/how-much-worth-is-half-a-promise/</guid>
      <description>If you are hungry, half a hamburger is better than nothing.
If you need to finance a project, raising only half of the money is better than no money at all. If you’re expecting a thousand people to read your article and only five hundred actually read it, this is still better than none.
Many times, half is better than nothing. But not always. What about half a promise?
 If you ask a baby sitter to come over… If you invite friends for dinner… If you need a partner for your project… If you want to marry…  …and the answer you get never surpasses a ”maybe”, I would call this giving half a promise.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>For Those Who Care</title>
      <link>http://egmontmika.com/blog/for-those-who-care/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Dec 2015 06:39:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://egmontmika.com/blog/for-those-who-care/</guid>
      <description>Jesus called us to make disciples. And making a disciple comes with a price.
It costs you your time, energy, and money. It calls for patience, wisdom and endurance. It&amp;rsquo;s a long-term commitment.
Now you may wonder: Am I really prepared for this? Is it possible for me to give more time, energy, and money? Am I patient enough, wise enough, and committed enough?
As to time, energy and money, the answer is pretty simple: You already have enough.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What&#39;s Your Response to Terror?</title>
      <link>http://egmontmika.com/blog/how-do-you-respond-to-terror/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Dec 2015 06:39:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://egmontmika.com/blog/how-do-you-respond-to-terror/</guid>
      <description>Paris, November 13th, 2015 !
Overwhelmed and horrified by what happened that night, I asked myself, What is my response to all those terror attacks in recent years, not only in the Middle East and in places “far away”, but also increasingly in Europe?
Will the horror stay with me and eventually leave me in a constant state of fear? Will it affect my attitude towards the world and the people around me, towards Muslims in general as well as towards my Muslim friends, colleagues, students and neighbours?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Walking the Bumpy Road</title>
      <link>http://egmontmika.com/blog/walking-the-bumpy-road/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Nov 2015 03:01:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://egmontmika.com/blog/walking-the-bumpy-road/</guid>
      <description>Are you looking for a safe and comfortable road to travel on?
Then, following Jesus might not be the right choice for you.
Jesus never invited anyone to a safe journey. Neither did his Father. The Bible is filled with stories about men and women who knew God and faithfully followed him on a rather bumpy road with many potholes, detours and dangers.
Just think of Abraham, Joseph, Moses, Elijah, David, Isaiah, Jeremiah, Jesus, Paul… Their lives were characterized by dangers, hardship, risks, threats, agonies and persecution.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Your Great Work</title>
      <link>http://egmontmika.com/blog/your-great-work/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Nov 2015 03:01:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://egmontmika.com/blog/your-great-work/</guid>
      <description>Great work doesn’t come out of nowhere.
And it’s not only a privilege for the talented.
Usually great work results from someone working hard and trying over and over again, failing included - many times.
Moreover, it&amp;rsquo;s risky.
It&amp;rsquo;s risky before you get started, and it&amp;rsquo;s risky all the way through until it&amp;rsquo;s finished. It can cost you everything; your time, your sleep, your comfort, your money, your reputation - and your pride.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Feeling Like a Failure?</title>
      <link>http://egmontmika.com/blog/feeling-like-a-failure/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Oct 2015 03:01:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://egmontmika.com/blog/feeling-like-a-failure/</guid>
      <description>Having failed isn&amp;rsquo;t the same as feeling like a failure.
Feeling like a failure can be much worse than the actual failure.
A failure in itself is just an event, not a feeling. It&amp;rsquo;s something specific that happened to you at a specific time in a specific place. Like you didn’t pass the test, couldn’t keep your promise, missed your flight, lost your credit card, or made a foolish comment.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Your Precious Failures</title>
      <link>http://egmontmika.com/blog/your-precious-failures/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Oct 2015 03:01:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://egmontmika.com/blog/your-precious-failures/</guid>
      <description>Nobody likes failures.
However, failures are more precious than most of us are inclined to think.
In fact, they can become stepping stones towards our final success. Don’t get me wrong, a failure really is a failure, not a success. It&amp;rsquo;s ugly, discouraging, accusing, threatening, judging! However&amp;hellip;
A failure doesn&amp;rsquo;t have to be the final word spoken. The crucial question is, what do you do with it? What comes next?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Full-Time, Part-Time or Spare-Time Ministry?</title>
      <link>http://egmontmika.com/blog/full-time-half-time-or-spare-time-ministry/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Sep 2015 06:39:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://egmontmika.com/blog/full-time-half-time-or-spare-time-ministry/</guid>
      <description>As a disciple of Jesus, do you have a full-time or a part-time ministry?
Or is yours &amp;ldquo;only&amp;rdquo; spare-time?
No matter what your answer is, following Jesus is neither one. If you are his disciple, you are what you are twenty-four hours a day, seven days a week. That’s neither full-time nor part-time nor spare-time.
That&amp;rsquo;s all-the-time!
The reason for that? Discipleship isn’t based on a service, a duty or a program.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Are You a Spiritual Leader?</title>
      <link>http://egmontmika.com/blog/are-you-a-spiritual-leader/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Sep 2015 06:39:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://egmontmika.com/blog/are-you-a-spiritual-leader/</guid>
      <description>Following Jesus rubs off.
As a disciple of Jesus, you influence your environment and the people around you. Discipleship often develops into leadership.
It’s a different kind of leadership, though. Different from what most people would expect. Often lacking the most typical characteristics that you usually associate with leadership, like power, position, title, status, money, popularity, image, good looks, high IQ, education, or whatever else impresses on people.
It’s an up-side-down leadership.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Share a Meal</title>
      <link>http://egmontmika.com/blog/share-a-meal/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Sep 2015 06:39:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://egmontmika.com/blog/share-a-meal/</guid>
      <description>Hospitality is an expression of God’s character.
Our Lord is a welcoming God. He is generous, nourishing, lavish, joyful…
He is hospitable.
And this is what we are communicating to others when being hospital. It’s as easy as sharing a meal with a friend, a colleague, a neighbor, or a stranger. Or why not a beggar! God is indiscriminate.
He is including.
Your meal doesn’t have to be fancy; don’t let it be exclusive.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mentorship - Respect, Freedom and Trust</title>
      <link>http://egmontmika.com/blog/respect-freedom-and-trust/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Aug 2015 06:39:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://egmontmika.com/blog/respect-freedom-and-trust/</guid>
      <description>Definition
When Jesus commanded his disciples to go out and make disciples, they understood this as building a master-disciple relationship. The apostle Paul translated it into his greco-roman world by instead talking about a father-son relationship. Today, we often use the term mentorship.
Still, it&amp;rsquo;s the same content, the same mission. It&amp;rsquo;s the mission that Jesus gave us.This is how I use this term in my blog.
 Mentorship - Respect, Freedom and Trust</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Give to the Lord...</title>
      <link>http://egmontmika.com/blog/give-to-the-lord/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Jun 2015 06:39:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://egmontmika.com/blog/give-to-the-lord/</guid>
      <description>Give to the Lord what he is asking you for!
No one is born as a disciple of Jesus, far less a disciple maker. Yet, this is what Jesus wants us to be, a disciple and a disciple maker.
Accordingly, somewhere along the road, there must be a turning point, or a new start. For every one of us.
We may argue that we are not gifted like evangelist so and so or pastor so and so…, but that’s not the point!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How You Can Learn Patience</title>
      <link>http://egmontmika.com/blog/how-you-can-learn-patience/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 May 2015 06:39:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://egmontmika.com/blog/how-you-can-learn-patience/</guid>
      <description>”I want patience, and I want it right NOW!!!”
The more you yell, the more you’ll miss it.
No one is born with patience, in fact, the opposite is true. And there is no short-cut to get it. No button to push, no recipe to follow, no course to attend. It’s nothing money can buy…
Patience is learned the hard way. Over time, and through suffering.
By suffering the pain of waiting.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Finding Simplicity</title>
      <link>http://egmontmika.com/blog/finding-simplicity/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 May 2015 06:39:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://egmontmika.com/blog/finding-simplicity/</guid>
      <description>Simplicity isn’t the same as poverty. Poverty is a curse, simplicity is an accomplishment.
The accomplishment of the wise.
Simplicity is obtainable. Everyone can achieve it, but not everyone will.
When you turn around and start following Jesus, many things will turn simpler for you.
This doesn’t mean that you flee from the complexity of life. Rather, you face and embrace it, and then simplify by making active choices.
You structure your hours and plan your activities in order to follow your calling and accomplish an aim.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Overcoming Fear</title>
      <link>http://egmontmika.com/blog/overcoming-fear/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Apr 2015 06:39:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://egmontmika.com/blog/overcoming-fear/</guid>
      <description>The enemy of faith is fear.
Fearing sickness, death and final judgement, fearing failure… Fearing what others might think of me, fearing their rejection. Or their complacency. Or fearing my boss, my bills, the weather or just anything that might happen in the future.
Before we meet God’s grace, the undercurrent of our life is fear. Fear makes us worry. It makes us live in a state of denial. Denying who we really are.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What&#39;s the Perfect Church?</title>
      <link>http://egmontmika.com/blog/whats-the-perfect-church/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Apr 2015 06:39:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://egmontmika.com/blog/whats-the-perfect-church/</guid>
      <description>There is no such thing as a perfect church. Most Christians agree on that!
Why then does it shock us when something happens in the church that absolutely should not have happened? Yes, of course, it’s okay if it happens in the world, but in the church, among the saints?!
Disgusting! How could this be!
But wait a minute! Why are we contradicting ourselves? In one breath we say the church isn’t perfect, and at the same time we act offended by its imperfections.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Faith Isn&#39;t Religion</title>
      <link>http://egmontmika.com/blog/faith-isnt-religion/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Apr 2015 06:39:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://egmontmika.com/blog/faith-isnt-religion/</guid>
      <description>Following Jesus calls for faith.
Yet, faith and religion aren’t the same. Faith isn’t religion.
Don’t confuse the two!
Typically, religion is made up of two components: There is a set of statements about what a group of people, an organization, a movement, or a society consider to be true. And there are rules, rituals and traditions to follow, as applications of these truths.
Faith, however, is beyond those things. It’s originated in another realm… it springs forth out of your spirit.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Disciple&#39;s Defeat and Victory</title>
      <link>http://egmontmika.com/blog/a-disciples-defeat-and-victory/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Mar 2015 03:01:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://egmontmika.com/blog/a-disciples-defeat-and-victory/</guid>
      <description>The road of discipleship is a rocky road.
And it’s an all but straight and upward leading walk. If you expected it to just take you from success to success and “from glory to glory”, you’ve probably never really tried it out.
In reality, walking that road doesn’t look that fantastic. Rather, it’s a slow and drawn-out process, much slower and way longer than we would imagine. And a lot messier than we would expect, filled with challenges, setbacks, failures, disappointments and unexpected turns.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Don&#39;t Work for God! </title>
      <link>http://egmontmika.com/blog/dont-work-for-god/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Mar 2015 03:01:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://egmontmika.com/blog/dont-work-for-god/</guid>
      <description>Don’t work for the Lord! Work with him!
Why are there so many discouraged and burned-out pastors? Why do so many leave the ministry? Didn’t Jesus say that his burden would be light?
Maybe ministry has become too heavy, because too much has been added by man. Too much of human ambitions and desires to influence and accomplish and control. Too much of duties, worries and fear.
Jesus simply expects us to follow him and make disciples.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Just Do It! </title>
      <link>http://egmontmika.com/blog/just-do-it/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Feb 2015 03:01:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://egmontmika.com/blog/just-do-it/</guid>
      <description>There is no better way of teaching and learning than the hands-on training in real life situations.
 If you want to learn how to walk, you&amp;rsquo;ll have to start walking. If you want to learn how to ride a bike, you&amp;rsquo;ll have to start biking. If you want to learn how to swim, you&amp;rsquo;ll have to start swimming.  No matter how lousy you may feel in the beginning, you&amp;rsquo;ll just have to do it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dealing with the Shameful</title>
      <link>http://egmontmika.com/blog/dealing-with-the-shameful/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2015 03:01:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://egmontmika.com/blog/dealing-with-the-shameful/</guid>
      <description>There are certain things I absolutely don’t feel happy to talk about.
Like telling another person how I made a fool of myself, or the number of times I reacted immaturely or arrogantly. Nor do I want to speak about the time I yelled and screamed and just couldn’t control my anger. But why should I?
Why should I expose myself and admit my failures? Why bother others with my private stuff?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ranking Jesus&#39; Words</title>
      <link>http://egmontmika.com/blog/ranking-jesus-words/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2015 03:01:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://egmontmika.com/blog/ranking-jesus-words/</guid>
      <description>Jesus said: “Go and make disciples!” As a disciple of Jesus, how do those words rank on your list?
When you think of your work, your spare time, your daily routines, and weekly obligations, including your spiritual engagements and church activities, where on that list would you place your response to Jesus’ words about making disciples?
Maybe you have already made some disciples, or just one, or maybe none. Or maybe you are just about to make one, or planning to.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Jesus Community</title>
      <link>http://egmontmika.com/blog/a-jesus-community/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2015 06:39:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://egmontmika.com/blog/a-jesus-community/</guid>
      <description>It doesn’t take a denomination to start a church.
Neither an apostle or a prophet, an appointed church leader or an official church planter. You can have a simple community of disciples and follow Jesus.
My wife and I do not hold any of these offices and we never formally started a church. In fact, we never attempted to.
However, there has been an informal community of disciples around us ever since we opened up our family and our home and let others join us in our walk with Jesus.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>God&#39;s Family - an Institution?</title>
      <link>http://egmontmika.com/blog/gods-family-an-institution/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2014 06:34:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://egmontmika.com/blog/gods-family-an-institution/</guid>
      <description>God wants a family. Yet, man builds him an institution.
Are you a father or a mother? Then imagine what it would feel like, if your children, as they grow up, turned your family into an institution.
What would that be like?
 Formal membership instead of family relations Organized meetings and programs at special times of the week instead of common family life Rented facilities instead of homes Formal, elected leadership instead of parenthood Board meetings instead of family counsel Democratic voting instead of common agreement Symbolic, formalistic eating and drinking instead of real meals Tithings, and offerings whenever you come together… (The list goes on.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dare Letting Go!</title>
      <link>http://egmontmika.com/blog/dare-letting-go/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2014 08:46:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://egmontmika.com/blog/dare-letting-go/</guid>
      <description>Do you want to move forward? Make a positive change in your life?
But feel stuck?
Are you stuck in your past? Or your debts, your reputation, your failures, your self-esteem, your weight? Your salary, your negative experiences&amp;hellip;? Is your spiritual life going in circles with mere religious routines and habits?
It’s easy to get stuck. And it’s easy to give up and stay where you are.
People spend huge amounts of time and money seeking to innovate and upgrade themselves, working to give up something, start or build something new, or change something about who they are and what they do.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Are You Quite Normal?</title>
      <link>http://egmontmika.com/blog/are-you-quite-normal/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2014 06:39:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://egmontmika.com/blog/are-you-quite-normal/</guid>
      <description>For being a disciple of Jesus, people may regard you as not being quite normal.
But what is ”normal”? In relation to what?
It could be many things, like eating breakfast in the morning, working during the day, watching the news in the evening, and sleeping at night. In that respect a disciple of Jesus wouldn&amp;rsquo;t necessarily stick out from the crowd and could be considered quite normal.
Yet, let&amp;rsquo;s think of some other more subtle aspects of life.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Brainwashing for You</title>
      <link>http://egmontmika.com/blog/brainwashing-for-you/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2014 06:59:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://egmontmika.com/blog/brainwashing-for-you/</guid>
      <description>Brainwashing – the cleansing of your mind – can be something quite positive. It all depends on who is doing it, how it is done, and what the purpose is. Just consider these words from an apostle:
 “Do not conform any longer to the pattern of this world, but be transformed by the renewing of your mind.” (Ro 12:2 NIV)
Again our questions of interest: Who is doing it, how is it done, and what is the purpose?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stepping out of the Boat</title>
      <link>http://egmontmika.com/blog/stepping-out-of-the-boat/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Oct 2014 07:26:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://egmontmika.com/blog/stepping-out-of-the-boat/</guid>
      <description>Jesus didn&amp;rsquo;t promise you a safe and predictable life.
Many times, following him may rather feel the opposite. Like stepping out of the boat and walking on water&amp;hellip;
What would that be like?
Setting a Jesus-standard First, it demands a clear decision for the standard you want to set. It&amp;rsquo;s not always a given choice; you’ll have to find out and understand what the Jesus-standard in your situation actually is.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>More than Receiving</title>
      <link>http://egmontmika.com/blog/more-than-receiving/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2014 17:57:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://egmontmika.com/blog/more-than-receiving/</guid>
      <description>Following Jesus is more than about receiving his blessings.
A major portion of contemporary church teaching and culture has its focus on the blessings of the New Covenant.
And to an extent this is right. As disciples of Jesus we are living in God’s grace and are richly blessed. There is godly love, forgiveness, healing, deliverance and potentially the restoration of all areas of life available to anyone who believes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What&#39;s Your Jesus Story?</title>
      <link>http://egmontmika.com/blog/whats-your-jesus-story/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2014 22:20:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://egmontmika.com/blog/whats-your-jesus-story/</guid>
      <description>Don&amp;rsquo;t miss sharing your very best story!
As a disciple of Jesus, you have your special story. It’s your story about that personal encounter with Jesus which caused you to respond to his call and surrender to him. It’s the story about how you “got saved”. It&amp;rsquo;s your Jesus story.
It isn’t necessarily something that is perceived by your natural senses. Nevertheless, it is very real and tangible and very powerful, something that has happened at a certain point of your life between you and Jesus, and between you and the Father.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jesus Conversations</title>
      <link>http://egmontmika.com/blog/jesus-conversations/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Sep 2014 19:53:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://egmontmika.com/blog/jesus-conversations/</guid>
      <description>The most precious, the most challenging and at the same time the most rewarding conversations I can think of are the missional conversations with someone who doesn’t know Jesus, yet.
These are those sweet moments of grace, when heaven touches the earth, with Jesus present and someone with an open heart at the same table with you. And as you continue to meet, you can see the Spirit working conviction, redemption and transformation - a new life is about to take form.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Being a &#34;Little Jesus&#34;</title>
      <link>http://egmontmika.com/blog/being-a-little-jesus/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Jun 2014 22:10:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://egmontmika.com/blog/being-a-little-jesus/</guid>
      <description>The task of discipleship is to represent Jesus. This means to embody man&amp;rsquo;s redemption through Him, and to express this new reality in all aspects of life.
It&amp;rsquo;s an individual task of every disciple as well as a corporate one, and it’s a goal as well as an ongoing, daily process. It&amp;rsquo;s the formation of the disciple into what C. S. Lewis called a “Little Jesus”.
To hand this on to every human soul is the essence of the Great Commission.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Running Ahead of Jesus</title>
      <link>http://egmontmika.com/blog/running-ahead-of-jesus/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 May 2014 07:33:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://egmontmika.com/blog/running-ahead-of-jesus/</guid>
      <description>As a disciple, don&amp;rsquo;t run ahead of Jesus! Let him go first.
That may include just about anything, but first of all it refers to our mission, to proclaim and to demonstrate his kingdom and to make disciples.
Jesus said, “Apart from me you can do nothing” (Jn 15:5), and I believe he meant it to be taken literally.
That&amp;rsquo;s, indeed, quite an authoritarian statement and nothing we would like to hear!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Revival the Jesus-Way</title>
      <link>http://egmontmika.com/blog/revival-the-jesus-way/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 May 2014 11:57:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://egmontmika.com/blog/revival-the-jesus-way/</guid>
      <description>Every revival seems to develop its own worship style and its specific methods and organisational structures for doing God’s work. And it’s quite legitimate to do so. New wine requires new wine skins.
However, it’s not the wine skin that makes the difference, but the wine. It’s not the worship style or a new style of preaching, teaching or praying that makes a revival. Electrically amplified sounds and flashy light effects by themselves do not add any spiritual value, neither is the presence of a large crowd in itself a sign for the Lord’s presence.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Filling the Emptiness of Waiting</title>
      <link>http://egmontmika.com/blog/filling-the-emptiness-of-waiting/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 May 2014 17:52:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://egmontmika.com/blog/filling-the-emptiness-of-waiting/</guid>
      <description>Have you ever spent a day or two in an overcrowded waiting room? Tired, sweaty, hungry, and bored to death - condemned to do nothing but wait?
I have been there, and I hated it. Those situations can quench your spirit and dry out your soul.
This makes me think of Nelson Mandela who spent more than 36 years of his life in a prison cell. What made this man survive mentally?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Partnering with Jesus</title>
      <link>http://egmontmika.com/blog/partnering-with-jesus/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2014 22:44:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://egmontmika.com/blog/partnering-with-jesus/</guid>
      <description>Jesus doesn’t want his followers to merely be attenders of church services.
His intent is to create a family, where common life is shared and mutual trust is cultivated. Moreover, he wants us to join him as partners in his mission.
As partners, we have been given the very same mission that the Father gave Jesus - not another mission. Our mandate simply is to proclaim and to demonstrate his kingdom in his name, and to make disciples.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Heavenly Music</title>
      <link>http://egmontmika.com/blog/heavenly-music/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Apr 2014 07:48:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://egmontmika.com/blog/heavenly-music/</guid>
      <description>Starting at the age of eight, I took piano lessons for ten years.
The lessons I was given were all about fingerings and techniques, about reading the notes and then playing more and more complex pieces. I did my best to practice these advanced compositions and somehow labored my way through them. I practiced and practiced and practiced&amp;hellip;
And yet&amp;hellip;
And yet, at no point did someone show me how to free myself from the slavery of those notes and actually make music.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Would You Like to Have a Mentor?</title>
      <link>http://egmontmika.com/blog/would-you-like-to-have-a-mentor/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Apr 2014 07:26:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://egmontmika.com/blog/would-you-like-to-have-a-mentor/</guid>
      <description>There are plenty of books available on discipleship. They tell you what a disciple is and how you can become a good one. Unfortunately, reading books on discipleship does not necessarily make you a disciple.
Real discipleship is worked out only through ’doing’, and doing something that you haven’t done before. Breaking a habit, stepping out into the unsafe, taking a risk, feeling uncomfortable for a while&amp;hellip; all these are part of becoming a disciple.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Imitating Jesus</title>
      <link>http://egmontmika.com/blog/imitating-jesus/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Apr 2014 13:15:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://egmontmika.com/blog/imitating-jesus/</guid>
      <description>I strongly dislike imitations.
There’s an honesty and a beauty with plain materials like wood, steel, stone, leather or wool, which an imitation can never achieve. Imitations are cheap, and they are fake. They are made for those who don&amp;rsquo;t have the feel for the real or just can’t afford it, yet want an illusion of the real stuff.
It&amp;rsquo;s similar with people. There is a unique beauty in every human being - especially when they are honest, natural and authentic, without any pretension.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What Are You Dreaming of?</title>
      <link>http://egmontmika.com/blog/what-are-you-dreaming-of/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Apr 2014 17:07:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://egmontmika.com/blog/what-are-you-dreaming-of/</guid>
      <description>It’s always inspiring to read about people who have accomplished great things in their lives, like Mahatma Gandhi, Martin Luther King, Nelson Mandela, Mother Teresa, Billy Graham&amp;hellip;
Or, who wouldn’t be touched by hearing about that African woman who started teaching other women to make baskets, which over the course of several years developed into a multi-million dollar business, and thereby giving a steady income to thousands of women in the villages around?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Walk the Talk</title>
      <link>http://egmontmika.com/blog/walk-the-talk/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Mar 2014 07:27:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://egmontmika.com/blog/walk-the-talk/</guid>
      <description>All of my five kids are brilliant cooks. At least that’s what I think. After all, they cook like their dad!
They are not merely recipe followers; they are creative and intuitive in their cooking style. For instance, they can develop their recipes on the go, and even whip up something exciting with almost nothing.
How did they become so skilful? I never enrolled them into a cooking school, never gathered them around the kitchen table for cooking class, and never once read a cooking book to them!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Applause Worth Living for</title>
      <link>http://egmontmika.com/blog/the-only-applause-worth-living-for/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Mar 2014 14:29:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://egmontmika.com/blog/the-only-applause-worth-living-for/</guid>
      <description>Everybody likes applause. It&amp;rsquo;s encouraging, uplifting, satisfying, flattering&amp;hellip; A professional performer will tell you that applause is far more than just an act of courtesy. It&amp;rsquo;s a reward, many times more worth than wages. It&amp;rsquo;s a necessity, something worth labouring and living for.
However, the crowd is unreliable, and their applause only momentary. People have a constant appetite for more, and they quickly forget about your past achievements.
They happily applaud you as long as you continue to meet their expectations and as long as they can celebrate you as their hero.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Break those Chains!</title>
      <link>http://egmontmika.com/blog/break-those-chains/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Mar 2014 15:37:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://egmontmika.com/blog/break-those-chains/</guid>
      <description>Jesus didn’t establish a chain of authority.
While some of his disciples expected to receive formal positions in his kingdom, Jesus refused to create a hierarchical system.
He said to them, “You know that the rulers of the Gentiles lord it over them and their high officials exercise authority over them. Not so among you.”(Mt 20:25 NIV)
Surprisingly and in spite of these words, most churches are organized as hierarchies, very much like public authorities or business companies, following a system of government that is in effect contrary to what Jesus had in mind.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Slippery Slope of Pleasing People</title>
      <link>http://egmontmika.com/blog/the-slippery-slope-of-pleasing-people/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Mar 2014 09:02:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://egmontmika.com/blog/the-slippery-slope-of-pleasing-people/</guid>
      <description>Doesn’t everyone want to be happy? And don’t we all like to hang around people who make us happy? Why not let maximizing people’s happiness be one of our foremost goals then? Wouldn’t that be a good way to serve humanity?
Interestingly, Jesus never spoke about happiness as a goal worth striving for, nor did he promise it to any of his followers. While showing mercy and compassion to those who came to him, he never allowed people’s needs or expectations to govern him.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>You Can&#39;t Cheat Jesus!</title>
      <link>http://egmontmika.com/blog/you-cant-cheat-jesus/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2014 20:10:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://egmontmika.com/blog/you-cant-cheat-jesus/</guid>
      <description>Is it possible to think of others and ourselves as being “good Christians” while actually being lousy followers of Jesus?
Or, is it possible to hold a prominent position in church, yet lack some basic Jesus-like character traits, like humility, mercy or a serving attitude?
As long as we keep our audience at a distance, it’s actually possible to pretend and to preach and teach beyond the level of our own spiritual life.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>More than Membership</title>
      <link>http://egmontmika.com/blog/more-than-membership/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2014 16:54:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://egmontmika.com/blog/more-than-membership/</guid>
      <description>Church membership doesn&amp;rsquo;t turn you into a disciple. We deceive ourselves when we think that membership has any long lasting spiritual significance. We can’t look to it as an indicator for our inner life or spiritual maturity, much less a guarantee for salvation. However, this is exactly what easily happens when we view ourselves and others within the subculture of our church or denomination. How do we, for example, assess the spiritual condition of our kids?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://egmontmika.com/blog/only-disciples-make-disciples/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://egmontmika.com/blog/only-disciples-make-disciples/</guid>
      <description>Institutions and offices cannot make disciples. Only disciples can.
Institutions can plan and execute, administrate and produce. They can influence and direct. And they can do a good job at all this!
The typical process how institutional churches are run starts with bringing people to “church”, engaging them in church activities and programs, making them agree to certain doctrinal beliefs, and socializing them into their specific church culture, with the ultimate goal of generating members and church workers.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
