<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blogs on Egmont Mika</title>
    <link>http://egmontmika.com/blog/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blogs on Egmont Mika</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 14 Feb 2018 03:01:45 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://egmontmika.com/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Overcoming Bitterness</title>
      <link>http://egmontmika.com/blog/overcoming-bitterness/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Feb 2018 03:01:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://egmontmika.com/blog/overcoming-bitterness/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Bitterness is a killer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Holding onto accusations hurts you more than anything else. Leaves you with a far greater damage than anything people can do to you. Bitterness steals your peace and breaks you down continuously. It kills you not only emotionally and spiritually, but also physically.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, what can you do in order to overcome? Here follow three steps:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Step 1&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first step is to stop.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Stop meditating on what happened. Stop accusing. Stop seeking revenge. Stop lamenting. Stop feeling sorry for yourself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just say, Stop!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Overcoming starts with this decision. Anyone can do it. You can do it, no matter whose guilt it is, no matter what the damage is, and no matter what your feelings are at the moment. Once you take that decision, eventually your feelings will follow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Step 2&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next step is to forgive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is the hardest part. You forgive, although the people who harmed you never regretted what they did, far less apologized. And don&amp;rsquo;t just think, I forgive you, but speak it out loudly so you can hear your own voice. Even better, let also someone else hear it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Call the person by name and shout it out, I don’t accuse you anymore! I forgive you! You are free!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Step 3&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The third step is to admit your own guilt.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yes, there is guilt with you, as well. In case you cannot think of anything to admit to this other person, at least admit your bitterness. Bitterness is sin. Again, do it loudly and in prayer. And be sure God will hear you and forgive you. He will heal you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And YOU are free. So precious!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Power of a Story</title>
      <link>http://egmontmika.com/blog/the-power-of-a-story/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Feb 2018 03:01:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://egmontmika.com/blog/the-power-of-a-story/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;In the beginning, God created&amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is how the probably most significant story of humanity begins. People have told this story for thousands of years, and it still is passed on from generation to generation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s the story of stories.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This story tells us where we come from and what our purpose is, and it connects us humans globally, across the borders of races, nations, and generations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s the story that tells us who we are.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To fully unfold its beauty and its power, you may want to hear it orally. Just knowing about it or being able to state its content does not give you the full experience. Writing it down or reading it word by word is much better, but still not quite the same as listening to it when being told orally.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To fully experience its power, you also may want to get hold of its unwritten values, beliefs, convictions, and experiences.
You may want to capture its spirit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Therefore, nothing matches up to listening to someone who tells the story orally and with conviction, who not only knows it by heart but loves it and has incorporated it into his or her own beliefs. Someone who has aligned with its spirit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then, the story truly becomes alive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then, this story enables us to transcend beyond our self-imposed differences, peering into a more fundamental realm of our existence, one more intrinsic to our nature than many of our rationalistic attempts to understand what human life is all about.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When we unleash the power of this story, it encourages us to strengthen bonds and build mutual trust.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And work for a shared future.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Art of Enjoying the Uncomfortable</title>
      <link>http://egmontmika.com/blog/the-art-of-enjoying-the-uncomfortable/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Jan 2018 03:01:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://egmontmika.com/blog/the-art-of-enjoying-the-uncomfortable/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Progress and comfort don’t match.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While not everything that is uncomfortable automatically will give you progress, there will always be a certain amount of inconvenience going along with it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Performance spikes when we’re doing something out of our norm.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is not only true for sports but probably for all areas of life, for instance, our spiritual life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Throughout Scripture, we find that following God’s call and striving for a comfortable life seem to contradict each other. Typically, responding to his call is associated with the requirement of stepping out and leaving. Leaving your family and friends, your familiar environment, and your securities. Changing some of your dear preferences and habits.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jesus never promised his disciples a comfortable life, yet, he expected them to be ”fruitful”.  For those who wanted to follow him, he pointed out what they could expect: inconveniences, uncertainty, mockery, hatred, and persecution.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Is this too much to expect?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It probably is, but not for those who have made up their minds. They are looking forward to their goal and consider it worthwhile the trouble. They know that hardship makes them achieve more than they ever dreamed possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They have learned to take advantage of the uncomfortable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And they enjoy it.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Three Steps to Overcome Worrying</title>
      <link>http://egmontmika.com/blog/three-steps-to-overcome-worrying/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jan 2018 03:01:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://egmontmika.com/blog/three-steps-to-overcome-worrying/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Worrying is NOT a virtue.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the contrary, it’s absolutely destructive. It’s a poison.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Worrying obscures your faith, weakens your strength, takes away your initiative, and quenches your creativity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It steals your joy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Worrying breaks you down spiritually, mentally, and physically. And it keeps you from doing your work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It keeps you from living your life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s easy to make people and circumstances responsible for your worries. Yet, they are not the producers. Worrying starts with a fearful thought in our own mind, with fearing things to get worse or something dreadful to happen. However, these things have not happened yet, and chances are, they will never happen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Worrying is a product of our mind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Outside of us, this fearful thought does not even exist, yet, to us it’s real. And by entertaining it, we let it slowly break down our spiritual and mental health, with possible symptoms even in our physical body.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How can we get rid of it? Here are three steps:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Take an intentional decision NOT to worry. Just refuse to submit to that thought.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Then, do whatever is possible for you to avoid whatever it is you fear.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Finally, focus on a better and higher goal and trust God that there will be a solution, in case things get worse.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jesus said, Do not worry! Seek first God’s kingdom! He sternly commanded his disciples not to fear and not to worry. Instead, he prompted them to prioritize God&amp;rsquo;s kingdom.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Worrying is worthless. It doesn&amp;rsquo;t change anything for the better.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, to take action and to trust God is wise.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is practicing your faith.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reconsidering Church</title>
      <link>http://egmontmika.com/blog/reconsidering_church/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Dec 2017 03:01:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://egmontmika.com/blog/reconsidering_church/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The status quo of the institutionalized church is powerful indeed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And we try to keep it alive by small improvements here and there, fancier equipment, trendier arrangements, and popular speakers. We add layers, patches, and small improvisations. Try to be modern.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All to save something we don&amp;rsquo;t want to reconsider.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We hardly ever question its basic structure, i. e., the institutional system, including constitutions, elections, offices, fundraising, buildings, and programs. Its division into clergy/professionals and laity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And its politics.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If we could start all over again and design something that actually would express the Kingdom of Heaven as proclaimed and put into practice by Jesus and the first century communities of disciples, what would we consider?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are some suggestions:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Purpose&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The mission of Jesus as the church&amp;rsquo;s ultimate purpose, to seek and save the lost. To reconcile them and to teach and train them as disciples, in order to send them out and do the same with others.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Community&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Community, not as an institution, but as a family.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Extended families and their homes as the basic units of the church in a city.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Not the building of a denomination, but the continuous multiplication of disciple communities as a viral movement.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Leadership&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Spirit-filled and Spirit appointed leadership.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The general priesthood of all disciples.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Practice&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The proclamation and demonstration of God’s kingdom in everyday life.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Seeking and saving the lost and training them as disciples on a personal level.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Authoritative preaching and teaching followed by signs.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The working of the gifts of the Spirit.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No matter, whether following a more traditional hierarchical or a more democratic system,
institutional churches easily fall into the trap of worldly management and business behavior.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Therefore, let us from time to time consider the original assignment and, whenever there is an opportunity, take the chance to break out of a misguiding system.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And start all over again.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Your Ways and His Ways</title>
      <link>http://egmontmika.com/blog/his%20ways/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Dec 2017 03:01:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://egmontmika.com/blog/his%20ways/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When you pray, who does most of the talking?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You or the Lord?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your answer will depend on where your focus is. Whether it is on yourself and your problems and desires, or on Him and His concerns.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On your ways or on His.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Depending on your focus you mostly either talk or listen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;God is looking for people who are eager to listen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He wants you to hear what He has to say and what He wants to do. He wants you to learn from Him and connect with His plans and His purposes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And become part of His ways.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;People who listen have switched their focus from ”I” and ”me” to ”You” and ”Your”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This changes your prayer radically.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now you see your own life and everyone around you in a new light. In His light. You look at them from His point of view, and you see what He is about to do and your part in it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a result, your long prayer talks will get shorter and shorter and will finally be reduced to a minimum, while the time you spend listening to Him will extend all the more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When listening, God’s ways become yours.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And your ways become His.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Controversial.</title>
      <link>http://egmontmika.com/blog/controversial/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Nov 2017 03:01:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://egmontmika.com/blog/controversial/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s not a bad thing to be controversial.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And it’s absolutely no sin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyone who stands up for what is right will meet opposition. The higher your position, the worse it can get. The stronger the rejection and the more disastrous the possible consequences.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The higher your purpose, the higher the cost.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With this in mind, it seems an easier way to adapt, to conform and be nice, trying to please as many as possible. Follow the public opinion, stay politically correct and socially accepted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sadly, this is where spiritual movements tend to end. After an initial period of radical commitment, many times ridiculed, despised and hated by its contemporaries, a movement slowly adapts and finally becomes well respected.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This has been the weakness of mainstream Christianity throughout the centuries. And it still is.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“When the salt loses its saltiness it’s not good for anything.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not so Jesus. Jesus was controversial. And he still is.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He never bowed under the pressure from his surroundings. Rather than calming down and taking it safe, he kept challenging his opponents to the uttermost.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He was able to stand up against the storm because he was willing to pay the price.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And he finally did.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As his followers, we need to be prepared for being controversial. Being controversial for a high goal can actually be a very good thing. Facing opposition helps you clarify your purpose, sharpen your focus and strengthen your will.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Shows what you go for.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For some of us, being controversial is more than something to suffer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s a necessity.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stand Up - Speak Up - Take Action!</title>
      <link>http://egmontmika.com/blog/what-do-you-stand-up-for/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Nov 2017 06:39:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://egmontmika.com/blog/what-do-you-stand-up-for/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Have you experienced this?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You know exactly what would be the right thing to do. Right now, you could change a situation for the better. Help someone, improve an organization, or turn a hopeless situation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yet, you hesitate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why do you back off?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Is it because of convenience? Or complacency? Or doubt?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Or because of the fear of being taken advantage of? Or because of possible risks? The fear of failure? Would the price be too high?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How can we overcome our inner resistance?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s when we pursue a higher purpose. When our goal is greater and stronger than our desire for comfort, security, and acceptance. Then, obstacles won&amp;rsquo;t scare us. Instead, they make us grow and overcome inner resistance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When we pursue an important cause and care enough to be willing to pay the price, we don&amp;rsquo;t let anyone or anything scare us. We take courage and get involved.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We speak up, stand up, and take action.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Do good.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jesus had such a purpose. Paul of Tarsus, Martin Luther King Jr., Mother Teresa and many others of his followers had.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And still have.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Like you and me.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Your Valuable Life</title>
      <link>http://egmontmika.com/blog/your-valuable-life2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Oct 2017 03:01:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://egmontmika.com/blog/your-valuable-life2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Life&amp;rsquo;s value is not defined by its highlights.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sunday worship services may leave the impression that living the Christian life is a series of elegant meetings. Jumping from celebration to celebration. Like a butterfly, from flower to flower. Looking for the next sensation, the next spiritual experience. With lots of smiles.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nothing could be more wrong than that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rather, it’s the other way around. Your valuable life is the life you live in between the highlights. It’s your daily walk. Including every day, every hour, every minute.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No part of your life is too low, not to be noticed. There is nothing to hide, nothing to be ashamed of, nothing unworthy. Everything counts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Everything is valuable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the Kingdom of God, there are no shadows. Everything is in His light. Also those moments when you come home from work feeling sweaty and dirty. Exhausted or maybe even discouraged. When you are sick or people have betrayed you and everything seems dark. Still, you are in His light. Still, your life is valuable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;YOU are valuable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One day, when you will look back and draw a balance, it will not be the highlights that added most value to your life, but your relationships. Your daily habits and your daily work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The fruit of your faithfulness and consistency.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And your love.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Power of Long-Term Commitment</title>
      <link>http://egmontmika.com/blog/the-power-of-commitment/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2017 03:01:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://egmontmika.com/blog/the-power-of-commitment/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Have you ever had a great idea? And tried to make it work?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tried to change something to the better? To accomplish something important and really worth the effort? Something that would improve your life and the world around you significantly?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Have you tried - and failed?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s easy to blame the opposition or people’s ignorance or the circumstances. Or the bureaucracy or the system…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s easy to blame and give up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, who promised you it would be easy?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If it was easy, you or others would have done it already. The fact that no one did it probably indicates that no one else saw the value of it or thought it was possible or was ready to pay the price. Or could do it for you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This means that it’s your turn!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, if you want to make it work you will have to be prepared to pay the price. Have faith against the odds and against what people say. Overcoming your fear. Battling the resistance from within and without. Being prepared to fail many times and learn from it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then, try again and endure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s consistent and persistent effort that leads to success. Great results aren’t accomplished by one try.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But a long-term commitment.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What Are You Waiting For?</title>
      <link>http://egmontmika.com/blog/what-are-you-waiting-for/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Sep 2017 03:01:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://egmontmika.com/blog/what-are-you-waiting-for/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Are you ready to make a disciple?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In case your answer is &amp;ldquo;no&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;not yet&amp;rdquo;, what would you still need?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jesus trained his disciples for only three and a half years, then sent them out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Where they fully educated then? - No.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Did they master the skills of an evangelist or preacher or teacher? - Probably not.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In fact, they hardly had the faith necessary, nor the skill, nor the understanding.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Still, Jesus sent them out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And whatever they were lacking, the Holy Spirit provided.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What they had learned by being with Jesus was not all they could have learned, if they had stayed with him for another decade, but it was good enough for a start.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What the Spirit needed in order to work through these people was not more education, but their willingness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Are you willing?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s face it! Believing that spending more time in church services will make you a better disciple maker is an illusion. In fact, it can be counterproductive. The longer you wait, the more you may want to stay. The less you may be willing to go out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Is that so?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If not, what are you waiting for?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Many Sermons Do You Need?</title>
      <link>http://egmontmika.com/blog/how-many-sermons/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Sep 2017 03:01:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://egmontmika.com/blog/how-many-sermons/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;How many sermons do you need in order to become a disciple?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Probably one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Or maybe a few. The rest is modelling.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yet, modelling is not done from the pulpit, but in everyday life. By sharing experiences, communicating kingdom values, demonstrating these values and explaining the hows and whys. Learning to listen to the Spirit and then follow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By taking action.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Admitted, preparation can take a life time. There will always be something more to learn, more to understand and more to prepare. Yet, when is a disciple ready to reach out and make another disciple?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How many sermons does it take a disciple to make another disciple?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Probably none. Again, disciple makers are not made from the pulpit, and not in classes. Speeches and curriculums won&amp;rsquo;t take you there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You&amp;rsquo;ll just have to do it. Jump the leap.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have been a disciple of Jesus for a while, let’s say, for a few months or a year or maybe even two, then you can do it. And if you still feel you need help, then find someone who is engaged in this kind of work and ask that person, if you may join him or her for a while. Just in order to turn the corner.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wouldn&amp;rsquo;t that be a good start?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Church and Money</title>
      <link>http://egmontmika.com/blog/church-and-money/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Aug 2017 03:01:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://egmontmika.com/blog/church-and-money/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;”It’s all about money!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is what we hear the critics say, while pointing at the large amounts of money collected by Christian ministries today.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;”No, it’s not true”, we answer, believing to have a better understanding. ”It’s all about Jesus and the Good News and about saving people for eternity. It’s about mission. Of course, this costs money. The more money we give, the more people we can reach.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In order to find out if this is true, let’s look at some statistics. How is the money spent and what is being accomplished?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to investigations from 2015, www.thetravelingteam.org, all church members around the globe gave in one year on average 1,7% of their income to churches. 2,9% of this money was used for mission inside their own countries and 0,3% for mission in unreached, non-christian countries.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, the largest part, 96,8%, was used for building the local church, that is, went mainly to salaries and buildings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In contrast, we are witnessing Christian movements in the third world, and not only there, with an unparallelled growth in history, yet, with very limited financial resources. These are grass-root movements, carried by the believers and their families, many of them poor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Moreover, some of these fast growing movements are operating under extremely difficult circumstances and even suffering persecution, like in China, South-Asia, and the Middle East. According to Open Doors every month hundreds of believers are killed because of their faith.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nevertheless this amazing growth!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s easy to think that we could accomplish so much more for the Lord, if we just had more money and could give more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Is that so?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building a Fortune</title>
      <link>http://egmontmika.com/blog/building-a-fortune/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jun 2017 03:01:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://egmontmika.com/blog/building-a-fortune/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;You can’t buy trust.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yet, it’s one of the greatest assets you can have. It’s a fortune.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At first glance, building trust seems simple. You say what you are going to do and then do what you said. You keep your promises. You act out your words. Never giving less, rather a little more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Without any hidden agenda, without cutting corners. Without faking the results. And without covering up your mistakes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Without pretending.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Showing up on time - doing your work - completing it. Period.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No need to make it look fancier. No need to add more or better promises. Just keep the ones you already made. No need to improve your image; it’s not a matter of marketing, anyway.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just be the person you say you are and do what is right.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s as simple as that, indeed. But alas! It’s not always easy. We hardly get it without effort and sometimes it takes great courage. And for some of us it just seems impossible, as long as we are hiding something.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In order to build a fortune of trust, you’ve got to be honest. Absolutely, radically honest. At times, and for a while, this may make you look like a looser.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is a price to pay.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the long run, though, reliabilty and honesty will pay and amount to much.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Hello friends!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This was my last blogpost for this season. The school year in Sweden is rapidly coming to an end and it&amp;rsquo;s time for a summer break.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thank you for reading my articles and joining me in the journey. I hope you enjoyed reading at least some of them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ll be back to you in September. Would you like to get a reminder by email? Then, make sure you have signed up by entering your email address in the top right corner of this page.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And, in case you never commented on any of my blogposts since last fall, this is the last chance you can do it. I&amp;rsquo;d love to hear from you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Have a nice summer.
Be blessed with the joy in the Lord!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yours,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Egmont&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Don&#39;t Go to Church!</title>
      <link>http://egmontmika.com/blog/don%27t-go-to-church/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 May 2017 03:01:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://egmontmika.com/blog/don%27t-go-to-church/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Church isn&amp;rsquo;t the same as a worship service.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nothing you &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;go to&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Neither a program nor an event. Far less a building, an organisation or a denomination. It wasn&amp;rsquo;t that from the beginning, and it still isn&amp;rsquo;t meant to be that today.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What is it, then?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s a family, a movement, a divine fellowship. A calling and a mission.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s what we are born into as followers of Jesus, redeemed through him, reconciled with our Father in heaven.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By his grace.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://molongnacua.com/being-church/?blogsub=confirmed#blog_subscription-3&#34;&gt;Molong Nacua&lt;/a&gt;, a Jesus follower from the Filipines, put it this way:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Church is where Christ lives, not the place where we meet. It is Christ-empowered people, a kingdom of priests for the purpose of winning against the works of the devil and establishing God&amp;rsquo;s Kingdom.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s about who we &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;are&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;. In Christ. Then follow him. Listen and obey. No matter where, no matter when - everywhere, at all times.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;go to&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; church. &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Be&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; church.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>